AKINOLA OLUTOLA

www.akinolaolutola.com, olutolamoses@gmail.com, +447946558765

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A 2+ year experience with a growth mindset and passion for solving real life problems through software applications. I have applied myself to build both back-end and front-end software applications in JavaScript and its many frameworks. I have collaborated in teams on several projects while also embodying a Do-It-Yourself (DIY) mindset to learn and implement innovative solutions.

SKILLS/COMPETENCIES

Heroku

Python/Selenium

Vue (Options API and SFC's)

NodeJS/Express

Oracle DB

Pivotal Tracker, Jira and Trello

MongoDB/Mongoose

Git

JavaScript/Typescript

EXPERIENCE

Stutern | Lagos, Nigeria

Software Engineer

March 2022 - till date

- Developed several technical solutions within agile environment and made changes based on stakeholder's feedback.
- Collaborated with different project stakeholders to come with up technical solutions to real life problems with effected changes based on product manager feedback.
- Wrote and maintained API documentations with swagger and used project management tools to track and monitor project's progress.

Innovation Lead

Guaranty Trust Bank | Lagos, Nigeria

Jan 2020 - August 2022

- Led a team across various banking divisions to propose innovative solutions to serve customers better in response to Covid-19.
- Ensured effective communication amongst team members and maintained information flow despite stiff business schedules amongst team members.
- Solutions were voted best with high adoption rate, cost effective with high possibility of revenue generation.
- Strategic creation off company's goals and objective, effective client management and relationship building.

Front-End Developer

Self-Employed

July 2021 – November 2021

- Partnered with UX designers to develop a web-based single page application.
- Replicated popular front-end designs such as Netflix and Jumia with pure HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript and webpack.
- Learnt a JavaScript framework and built web applications with the Vue options API.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

MSc. Artificial Intelligence and Data Analytics - Current
Bradford University

BSc. Anatomy
Babcock University

Python Fundamentals
Udacity

Front End Development
Pirple

Mobile Web Developer Google Developers

May 2022